<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/Books.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2011-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Book: The age of entanglement</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/book-the-age-of-entanglement" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2011-11-05:blog/book-the-age-of-entanglement</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is just a collection of small excerpts from the book that I deliberately did not mark in the book itself. There are a few reasons for this and I will put some prominent ones as briefly as possible. I believe that in itself will become a review, using the excerpt-ionism as the scapegoat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the text copyrights belong to Ms. Louisa Gilder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excerpts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 57. On the streetcar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bohr, Einstein and Sommerfeld are discussing nature of light and two theories – particle nature vs wave. They miss their stop by 12 stops while discussing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“well….” says Bohr as he sits down, “I suppose during a stage in science when everything is in ferment, it cannot be expected that everybody has the same views about everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein smiles at this. “No, that is something that cannot even in the best of circumstances be expected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 81, Heisenberg in Helgoland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, out of the blue and practically crossing paths on the mail, came a paper conveying a totally different quantum mechanics. It seemed to completely contradict Heisenberg’s, yet it produced all of the same results, and – far from the thicket of matrices – did so using mathematics that any physicist could command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Schrodinger equation had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 86, What can you observe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein sat down in one of his big armchairs before the unlit fire. “Heisenberg, he said, “every theory contains unobservable quantities.” Heisenberg looked up in surprise. “the principle of employing only observable quantities simply cannot be consistently carried out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But isn’t that precisely what you’ve been doing with relativity?” asked Heisenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein smiled a little. “Perhaps I did use such philosophy earlier, perhaps I even wrote it, but it is nonsense all the same.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heisenberg looked as if he were being told by his priest that he did not actually believed in God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 113, Solvay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Like a game of chess, Einstein all the time with new examples,” Ehrenfest described to his students the subsequent Bohr-Einstein debate, which filled all the extracurricular conference time. Considering his own distaste for both unclear speaking and smelly pipe smoke, Ehrenfest found apt metaphors at hand: “Bohr from out of the philosophical smoke clouds constantly searching for the tools to crush one example after the other. Einstein like a jack-in-the-box; jumping out fresh every morning. Oh, that was priceless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, after Einstein had asked for the umpteenth time if Bohr really believed that God played dice to determine the future, a smile dawned on Bohr’s face. “Einstein,” he said, “stop telling God how to run the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 134, Things fall apart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Von Neumann’s book was a tour de force of elegant and fearsome mathematics, the sort of things most physicists never read, but its existence and conclusions were deeply consoling. The phrase “von Neumann has shown…” entered the quantum physicist’s lexicon as a debate ender.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 136, Things fall apart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurs at the Cavendish lab experiment, the Rutherford’s place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rutherford stormed good-naturedly in and out, giving orders, encouragment, or distraction, occasionally shocking himself by hanging his wet coat on the live terminal or lighting overdry tobacco and sending it up “like a volcano with a great cloud of smoke, flames, and piles of ash,”as the experimentalist next door to Crockfort and Walton noticed with amusement. And on either April 13 or 14 – Crockfort and Walton in their notebooks wrote different dates – he observed the scintillations as the pieces of the atom hit the fluorescent screen. We’ve split the atom! This jubilant cry was soon heard at the newspapers – the atom, the unsplittable, has been split. Things fall apart; the center cannot hold.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 160, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small piece after the EPR paper from Einstein, Podolsky, Rosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While we have thus shown that the wave function does not provide a complete description of the physical reality, we have left open the question of whether or not such a description exists. We believe, however, that such a theory is possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podolsky had to leave for California at about the time of paper’s submission, and it is not clear that Einstein saw it before he was suddenly confronted, on May 4, 1935 (eleven days before the paper appeared in Physical Review), with an article on page 11 of the Saturday New York Times entitled “EINSTEIN ATTACKS QUANTUM THEORY,” complete with a hundred-word exegesis that the newspaper attributed to Podolsky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 168, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
It all came down to the relationship of Schrödinger’s equation to reality. What is the connection between the mathematical description of events, and the events themselves? In what way does the Schrödinger wavefunction, Ψ, reflect the actual state that a particle fount itself in? Reality, or the particle’s real situation, is represented in these discussions by the word state or the phrase state of affairs. The wavefunction, Ψ, must represent this real state of affairs somehow. But it is hard to even articulate what was meant by such a connection to reality, or even what was meant by reality or state.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 176, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…And even in when entering on topics apparently far removed from the problems under debate at our meetingsI have, so to speak, been arguing with Einstein all the time.”
Moved, Pais looked up at Bohr, whose voice was dropping as he circled. “I have been arguing with Einstein all the time…I have been arguing with Einstein…” He paced, slower and slower, hands behind his back, muttering, “Einstein…Einstein…” and finally stopped, gazing out the window, without seeing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assistant’s door soundlessly swung open behind him, and Einstein himself tiptoed into the room. There was “an urchin smile on his face,” and he signaled to Pais to be silent. “I was at a loss what to do,” remembered Pais, “especially because I had at that moment not the faintest idea of what Einstein was up to.” Very quietly Einstein lifted the lid of Bohr’s tobacco pot, and began to fill his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that moment, Bohr got his thought and spun around. “Einstein is -” and he stopped in complete shock. “There they were, face to face, as if Bohr had summoned his forth.” wrote Pais. “It is an understatement to say that for a moment Bohr was speechless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am sorry, Bohr,” said Einstein, as Bohr burst out laughing. “But you know my doctor forbade me to buy tobacco.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 177, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neils Bohr died next year. On his blackboard were left two drawings, a record of what he had been thinking about the night before he died. The first looked like a spiral staircase – A Riemann surface – which was Bohr’s favorite metaphor for the ambiguity of language, the way you can arrive back at the same word in your thought and it can have a whole new layer of meaning than when you first thought it. But how, he used to ask, can you communicate this to another person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second drawing, almost vibrating on its chalky spring, was Einstein’s light-filled box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 185, The Search And The Idictment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
David Bohm is called before committee…
“He used to joke about it,” remembered his student Ken Ford, “real gallows humor. There was a faculty lecture on unresolvable paradoxes – If the barder is the man who shaves all men, who do not shave themselves, who shaves the barder? – “and Dave said that ‘Congress should appoint a committee to investigate all committees that do not investigate themselves.’”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Book Review: CSS Mastery</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/book-review-css-mastery" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2010-09-24:blog/book-review-css-mastery</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amzn.com/1430223979"&gt;CSS Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, it seems, is for anyone who works with CSS. It is a very helpful book for people who are new to CSS and want a well-written book that is easy to understand. I found the book extremely helpful as a thorough read and as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://andybudd.com/"&gt;Andy Budd&lt;/a&gt;, is a famous UX and Usability specialist. He has done a nice job with this book. To be honest, I actually have some permanent bookmarks that I go to when I need advice. Be it the foundations or the bugs chapter, they are worth keeping bookmarked. He starts with structuring your code, teaching better semantics and strategies. He also covers various techniques which are important as a CSS developer like FIR. I also like that he covered formatting links, lists and forms. At the end of the book, there are two great case-studies which are very helpful for someone who wants to begin front-end web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just have one gripe which is not a big anyway. I hope that he had a separate chapter or section for CSS3 standard rather than it being within each chapter. A separate section would have been awesome for people who are trying to get on the CSS3 bandwagon. In short, this is a great book for a day-to-day CSS developer to keep by his/her side.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>