<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/Thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Customer Management Effort</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/customer-management-effort" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-01-14:blog/customer-management-effort</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is just a collection two nice personal customer management stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity Water&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I donated some money to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.charitywater.org"&gt;Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;. I have donated money to some of the well-known organizations, from large sized to some smaller than Charity Water. I have never received a hand-written, address-to-me letter/card from any organization before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Letter from charity water, scanned copy" class="align-center" src="http://amanjeev.com/img/charity_water_card.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 406px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amanjeev.com/img/charity_water_card.jpg"&gt;You can see a scanned copy of the card from Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I have been wondering if this is the right thing to do. It seems obvious that this is a very good strategy to thank the existing customers and keep them happy. I know that this is an effort to make things more personal for me and it feels great. I donated to their cause so I already was aligned with what they are doing and this personally written letter makes it easy to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is the first charity to explicitly mention it to me that a 100% of my donations will go to the cause. This maybe a minor thing but I felt that this was a nice little statement to get my trust. Thank you Charity Water for sending a card to me that looks like you put an effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BustedTees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company knows how to please their customers. I ordered a bunch of T-shirts and a few crazy things from them a while ago and asked for a 2-day shipping. For some reason, on the 4th day I suspected that my package was stolen or misplaced. I called their customer service with only the order number in my hand. It took about 3 minutes for the entire conversation for the customer representative to arrive at a conclusion - &lt;em&gt;Ship me another order with the same items immediately&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;And they did!&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later I also recieved the original package. Luckily, BustedTees had already sent me a UPS box to return the extra items. I had to do, nothing expect for making that call to their customer service department.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I have an Indian passport but I need Nationality Verification form. What!?</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-07-15:blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you are looking for the Nationality Verification form of India then you may want to go to the website of Consulate General. I do not take any responsibility of anything. This blog post is a rant.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to get my passport renewed. As expected the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indiacgny.org/"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indianembassy.org/"&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://indiacgny.org/php/showContent.php?linkid=225"&gt;portals&lt;/a&gt; of Indian government are useless. Fortunately, they have outsourced the process to another company – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/"&gt;VFS Global&lt;/a&gt;. So, I stumbled upon the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/india/usa/addition_of_spouse_docreq.html"&gt;Documents Required page&lt;/a&gt;. That’s where the funny part is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Print out of Online Application form (Total of 4 pages). (When you click this link, if your browser says ‘There is a problem with the website security certificate’, &lt;em&gt;then please click the option 'Continue to this website (not recommended)'. This is because the link is an external site but is reliable as it is maintained by Government of India)&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the government cannot reliably provide the information, I am not sure if I can call other resources of it being reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in that list there is a required form -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Nationality Verification Form&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am giving my passport (issued by the Government of India) to them (the Government) and they want to see another form that proves my nationality. Is there any other way you can get a passport of India? Maybe someone can enlighten me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jammukashmir.nic.in/"&gt;The website of the beautiful state of Jammu and Kashmir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>