<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2013-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Photography and Charity</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/photography-and-charity" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-09-11:blog/photography-and-charity</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this excellent photographer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://earthincolors.wordpress.com"&gt;Moyan Brenn&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aigle_dore/"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/Moyan_brenn"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;], who happens to have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://earthincolors.wordpress.com/my-international-charity-campaign/"&gt;charity campaign&lt;/a&gt;. On his charity web page where he urges everyone to join. He says -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Every month i am personally sending 20 dollars to a little boy in Africa……with my photo gallery i’m trying to involve people in donating money to the third world….it’s my main objective and why i want my pictures to be spread over the world. I have something beautiful to communicate which lies behind the strong colors of my pictures, and want it to be useful for those suffering in the third world&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He goes on to explain further on how you can join the charity campaign -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, optionally, if you can afford it and you really appreciate my works, I kindly invite you to make a donation, or to help me to diffuse my pictures by linking my blog in your website just if you decide to use my pictures, or, still, by inviting other people to use them for free and to donate as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do it, by sending me a receipt of the donation by email, your name will be inserted in the acknowledgement list below, and in the acknowledgement list reported in my flickr profile, where i will also include a link to your website or blog if you need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed it and have not visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aigle_dore/"&gt;his flickr&lt;/a&gt;, you should do that now because he really is a great photographer and I am sure a lot of us can make use of his photographs and skills. I also really liked the idea and model of his charity. He is passionate about photography and charity and he is achieving both here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally have mentioned my charity effort on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/amanjeev"&gt;my 500px page&lt;/a&gt; as -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Any purchase of my pictures or any donation for my work will go to the humanitarian causes. I am not affiliated to these organizations and you are free to donate to these yourself.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.prajwalaindia.com/home.html"&gt;Prajwala&lt;/a&gt; [for the victims of sex trafficking]&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, so far I have &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16964325"&gt;sold only one photograph&lt;/a&gt; (amounts to $2 at this point). Then this morning I realized that maybe people are skeptic of such purchases. Maybe, they think that I am raking in cash and not donating (although looking at my amateur skills, it is evident I ain't selling a lot). I'd be skeptic about this too. Funny that when we donate to a charity, the transparency we demand from the charity is so high. I wish we did this with for-profit companies also. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/500px_Help/status/377788159100452864"&gt;I contacted 500px over twitter&lt;/a&gt; regarding this. The idea is simple - prove the authenticity of a photographer's charity status to the potential buyers. Here are some key points that I thought of -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500px acts as a mediator between charities/non-profits and photographer's purchases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One can easily connect to and build a list of various non-profits around the globe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographers can display how much percentage of their profits from 500px do they want to donate to the charities but this will be displayed on their profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since, 500px is the mediator, they can control these donations and award a so called - Charity Badge - to the photographer to be displayed on the profile. This alone will give confidence of the users/buyers to purchase something from someone who donates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographers can also list non-profits they donate to on their respective profile to facilitate this further. The more details in the profile, more will be user confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unaware of the legalities involved but I don't see how it will be a big deal, except that 500px will have to do a lot of work and being a startup they might have to run the numbers on how beneficial this will be for them. So, maybe we (the Phogrammers or Protographers) can use 500px's API to create a service that lets people achieve this without 500px having to do all the work? I am not sure yet, but I think this is a start in some kind of charity campaign that can get passionate photographers make an effort to sell more and buyers of their work to make more humanitarian choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding my mother's date of birth</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/finding-my-mothers-date-of-birth" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-06-28:blog/finding-my-mothers-date-of-birth</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is not a rant but rather a small story about my mother. She was born in a relatively upper-middle class family back in 1958. It is best to mention right now, that on the surface she does not seem like a victim of gender abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was old enough to know what &lt;em&gt;birthday&lt;/em&gt; meant, I was as excited as any other kid. I got gifts, presents and kudos for just being born on that day, though only by chance. At that time, it was important to just get as many &lt;em&gt;presents&lt;/em&gt; as I could while it's still &lt;em&gt;my day&lt;/em&gt;. After all, it would take a year for it to be today. One day, when I was young enough to not question the involvement of chance in my birth, I asked my mother about her birthday. Needless to say, I was shocked to learn that she had no idea about her actual date of birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;I was the second girl child in the family, so they wept and mourned when I was born, and no one cared to remember the date. When they had to get my birth certificate for school, they scribbled a random date which became my date of birth.&amp;quot;, she replied.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that was India more than 60 years ago. A country where you can still forge a driver's license easily, to get anything on your birth certificate would have been extremely easy in that era. Moreover, a lot of deliveries at that time were conducted through midwives at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, the spectrum of emotions I feel when I think about that statement. I used to think that everyone has as loving, supportive and motivating parents as I have, despite their gender. How can anyone's parents forget their child's birthday?! It changed my world, completely. It was the first time I started observing how a male child in India can take everything for granted, started witnessing the extreme patriarchal setup. For example, it was, and still is assumed that the woman will change her last name after marriage; often, first names are also changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She spoke to a lot of elders (mostly aunts) in the family who were around the time of her birth. She heard the following pointers from her aunts -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You were probably born on a Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You were born during the monsoon season or it was raining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were the second female child so no one remembers because everyone was mourning your birth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not end there. Like almost every person during that time, she had to get married to someone her parents chose. The argument in favor of arranged marriage that I have been told again and again is that parents know better about their children than the children themselves. In my mother's case, her father promised her to my father &lt;em&gt;without even meeting him or anyone from his family&lt;/em&gt;. I do not even want to begin mentioning how my mother's in-laws treated her the rest of her life but I blame that mainly on her own parents. It is hard for others to appreciate your kids when you don't appear to be caring about them youself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was a brilliant student and studied almost her entire student life on scholarships. She was the university topper in her subject - History - which was not her first choice. Her first passion was Biology and she wanted to study medical science. Obviously, she had to pass being a doctor because her father told her that one her brothers will be a doctor. He was given preference because, obviously, he's a boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother's parents are not alone in this grotesque treatment and this is not the worse story. For a country that boasts a plethora of goddesses in its culture, stories like my mom's throw light on this hypocrisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this about India is just a regular web search away but I wanted to write this little part of my mother's life story because it is her birthday this week. I salute her for being so brave at every step of her life, starting from the first day of her birth.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>List of some Vim commands</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/list-of-some-vim-commands" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-04-20:blog/list-of-some-vim-commands</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a list, nothing special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reformats the selected text according to the current indent rules&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
=
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Auto-indent current line&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
==
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;If you make a lot of edits, then undo them, then make one more edit, then decide you want the first set of edits back, most editors can't do it.  Emacs can, but it's a pain.  g- in Vim will usually take you straight there. This is not available in Vi.&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
g-
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Jump to the corresponding sibling item like open/close brackets - (), {}, []. Or HTML tags&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
%
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Center your screen on the current line&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
zz
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;In command mode, this goes to insert mode at the last place you were in the insert mode&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
gi
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Example, record with qa and replay with &amp;#64;a&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
Recording with : q&amp;lt;character&amp;gt;
Replay with    : &amp;#64;&amp;lt;character&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To reload the file you are currently editing. This helps when you are editing .gvimrc or .vimrc files in Vim and you want to reload the changes&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
:so %
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Vertical split and horizontal split window, respectively. A lot of combinations are available. They take a command to not duplicate the window by default and open the one you specify&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
:vsp
:sp
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To make splitting more intuitive&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
set splitbelow
set splitright
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To map moving between the buffer splits more intuitive with c-hjkl&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;C-J&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-W&amp;gt;&amp;lt;C-J&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;C-K&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-W&amp;gt;&amp;lt;C-K&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;C-L&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-W&amp;gt;&amp;lt;C-L&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;C-H&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-W&amp;gt;&amp;lt;C-H&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Max out the height of the current split&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
ctrl + w _
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Max out the width of the current split&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
ctrl + w |
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Normalize all split sizes, which is very handy when resizing terminal&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
ctrl + w =
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Swap top/bottom or left/right split&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
Ctrl+W R
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Break out current window into a new tabview&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
Ctrl+W T
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Close every window in the current tabview but the current one&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;pre class="first last literal-block"&gt;
Ctrl+W o
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/vim-setup/blob/master/.gvimrc"&gt;My .gvimrc file on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/terryma/vim-multiple-cursors"&gt;Vim Multiple Cursors plugin like Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/48275867281/vim-splits-move-faster-and-more-naturally"&gt;Vim Splits - Move Faster and More Naturally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=1658"&gt;NERDTree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Pelican + Foundation</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/pelican-foundation" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-02-24:blog/pelican-foundation</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an absolutely new site which is statically generated using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. The framework used is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://foundation.zurb.com/"&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican requires a theme which can be anything but I created a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/foundation_pelican"&gt;theme from Foundation - [Github Repository]&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/amanjeev.com"&gt;here is the final source for amanjeev.com (this site)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only trouble I had was that Pelican by default requires the home page to be a blog. That means, the home page is paginated. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican/pull/623"&gt;There is a solution&lt;/a&gt; that makes it possible to have home page as a static page (reST or Markdown) and move your blog page to some other URL like /blog.html. I could have used it but I saw two opportunities in the code -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To have the home page still be a dynamic page with dynamic listing of the latest posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be able to specify all the new templates that you add as &lt;em&gt;paginated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/pelican/commit/71ca51acc5d3ffe8e220b42a9280a614872fb03f"&gt;made some changes&lt;/a&gt; which are clearly not official and live on a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/pelican/tree/nobloghome"&gt;separate branch&lt;/a&gt;. There is indeed a lot of discussion needed and the Gods of the project will know more than I do at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is some discussion that has started on the archive pages. I clearly think that the archive pages need pagination and the default page limit value must be different than that of the normal pagination for the blog posts. Archives page has considerably less data so a default value of &lt;em&gt;DEFAULT_PAGINATION&lt;/em&gt;, which is usually around 5 to 10, does not work for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican/issues/735"&gt;Github issue&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to chime in.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Customer Management Effort</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/customer-management-effort" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-01-14:blog/customer-management-effort</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is just a collection two nice personal customer management stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="charity-water"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charity Water&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I donated some money to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.charitywater.org"&gt;Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;. I have donated money to some of the well-known organizations, from large sized to some smaller than Charity Water. I have never received a hand-written, address-to-me letter/card from any organization before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Letter from charity water, scanned copy" class="align-center" src="/img/charity_water_card.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 406px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amanjeev.com/img/charity_water_card.jpg"&gt;You can see a scanned copy of the card from Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I have been wondering if this is the right thing to do. It seems obvious that this is a very good strategy to thank the existing customers and keep them happy. I know that this is an effort to make things more personal for me and it feels great. I donated to their cause so I already was aligned with what they are doing and this personally written letter makes it easy to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is the first charity to explicitly mention it to me that a 100% of my donations will go to the cause. This maybe a minor thing but I felt that this was a nice little statement to get my trust. Thank you Charity Water for sending a card to me that looks like you put an effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bustedtees"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BustedTees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company knows how to please their customers. I ordered a bunch of T-shirts and a few crazy things from them a while ago and asked for a 2-day shipping. For some reason, on the 4th day I suspected that my package was stolen or misplaced. I called their customer service with only the order number in my hand. It took about 3 minutes for the entire conversation for the customer representative to arrive at a conclusion - &lt;em&gt;Ship me another order with the same items immediately&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;And they did!&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later I also recieved the original package. Luckily, BustedTees had already sent me a UPS box to return the extra items. I had to do, nothing expect for making that call to their customer service department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Photo: Unused bench gathers a lot of moss</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-10-21:blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="http://pcdn.500px.net/16341429/ea700652f238ad65807bdfe9c06ff1f5b0a92a15/4.jpg" src="http://pcdn.500px.net/16341429/ea700652f238ad65807bdfe9c06ff1f5b0a92a15/4.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341429"&gt;Unused bench gathers a lot of moss&lt;/a&gt; is now in the Popular pictures’ set on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/"&gt;500px (the photography website)&lt;/a&gt;. I also have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341455"&gt;B&amp;amp;W version of this picture&lt;/a&gt; which has amazing texture of this bench but I guess more folks in the world have better/more &lt;cite&gt;cone cells&lt;/cite&gt; in their eyes than I do. My response to the B&amp;amp;W picture was more positive than this one, even though I love this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken in the American University, Washington D.C. Photography can be very unpredictable when it comes to subjects. One can have as many themes and one can keep on shooting the entire day but the best piece of the day may certainly be something you just randomly clicked. For my future self, I need to remember two things -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click more and more. I am not paying for the film so why not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step outside of the subject boundary and not be confined. This will take a lot of effort despite the fact that I know it very well that I have to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck because this is a fortuitous profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>10000</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/10000" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-09-21:blog/10000</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I believe that every computer programmer should know about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html"&gt;Norvig’s Teach Yourself Programming in Ten Years&lt;/a&gt;. If you have not read it, give it a go. It is an excellent piece of advice. So, if you have not heard about the 10,000 hour rule then you should also read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316017930/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=profeblogs0df-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0316017930"&gt;Outliers: The Story of Success&lt;/a&gt; by Malcolm Gladwell. The author is trying to say that to be a ‘superlative’ in your trade, you need to invest 10,000 hours in it. To be clear, 10,000 hours is the rule not to be just good or very good; it is to be somebody who is unrivaled in that trade. This, according to Mr. Gladwell, applies everywhere. So, this should apply to Photography as well. I recently started photography as a hobby and very recently read this quote -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;Your first 10,000 photographs are your worst.&amp;quot; -Henri Cartier-Bresson&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have some doubts. Here are some&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are those 10,000 hours related to 10,000 photographs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, what kind of 10,000 photographs are those?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do multiple shots of one object/subject count as one photograph or multiple?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How about shots that you take while testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>If you talk about your interests, my eyes might glaze over</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/if-you-talk-about-your-interests-my-eyes-might-glaze-over" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-08-10:blog/if-you-talk-about-your-interests-my-eyes-might-glaze-over</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a fan of Dan Dennett and I have always enjoyed his talks. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_dennett_on_our_consciousness.html"&gt;This talk&lt;/a&gt; has a starting quote that made me laugh (and think) -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m going to speak about a problem that I have and that’s that I’m a philosopher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I go to a party and people ask me what do I do and I say, “I’m a professor,” their eyes glaze over. When I go to an academic cocktail party and there are all the professors around, they ask me what field I’m in and I say, “philosophy” — their eyes glaze over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I go to a philosopher’s party and they ask me what I work on and I say, “consciousness,” their eyes don’t glaze over — their lips curl into a snarl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I have an Indian passport but I need Nationality Verification form. What!?</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-07-15:blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you are looking for the Nationality Verification form of India then you may want to go to the website of Consulate General. I do not take any responsibility of anything. This blog post is a rant.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to get my passport renewed. As expected the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indiacgny.org/"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indianembassy.org/"&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://indiacgny.org/php/showContent.php?linkid=225"&gt;portals&lt;/a&gt; of Indian government are useless. Fortunately, they have outsourced the process to another company – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/"&gt;VFS Global&lt;/a&gt;. So, I stumbled upon the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/india/usa/addition_of_spouse_docreq.html"&gt;Documents Required page&lt;/a&gt;. That’s where the funny part is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Print out of Online Application form (Total of 4 pages). (When you click this link, if your browser says ‘There is a problem with the website security certificate’, &lt;em&gt;then please click the option 'Continue to this website (not recommended)'. This is because the link is an external site but is reliable as it is maintained by Government of India)&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the government cannot reliably provide the information, I am not sure if I can call other resources of it being reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in that list there is a required form -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Nationality Verification Form&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am giving my passport (issued by the Government of India) to them (the Government) and they want to see another form that proves my nationality. Is there any other way you can get a passport of India? Maybe someone can enlighten me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jammukashmir.nic.in/"&gt;The website of the beautiful state of Jammu and Kashmir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Macho Developers and the Clique</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/macho-developers-and-the-clique" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-07-13:blog/macho-developers-and-the-clique</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently met someone during my travel to work, in the train. I will not name this certain someone but just know that he is apparently a talented FOSS contributor and is related to GNU.org. I will call him Mr. X. In general, X was friendly. He caught me writing some code in the train and assumed I was writing JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: Are you writing JavaScript?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: Anything that colorful could only be JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ (ummmm... it's the editor]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Are you a programmer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: I don’t write JavaScript. I am a C hacker. Kernel hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[At this point I did not realize there was a bit mocking tone to his &amp;quot;I don't write JavaScript&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I didn’t have to ask a lot and a lot of talking was done by Mr. X. Mostly nice talk but a couple of things however, got stuck with me since that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The clique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, “He does not write anything that cannot be written with C“. There was a sense of superiority in his style of conversation. “Moi poor web developer”, I thought. I like open-source software and use it everyday. I really wish that this attitude changes amongst the developer community. I really respect your knowledge but it hurts if you lack humility and respect for others, especially the ones who aspire to contribute and support the open-source software and community. This attitude makes it harder for everyone. I am glad that there are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kennethreitz.com/be-cordial-or-be-on-your-way.html"&gt;posts like this&lt;/a&gt; which support this view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Us Macho Programmers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/macho"&gt;macho&lt;/a&gt; : aggressively virile; a man who is aggressively proud of his masculinity.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard the phrase Us macho programmers at least thrice in the conversation. I do not appreciate this. What this conveys to me is that the real programmers are the knights, which in turn, are only masculine. This equates macho with programmers. I have nothing much to say on this issue except that it discouraged me from pursuing being a part of this group he was talking about which I mentioned about in the clique. If I, a male programmer, got discouraged then I can’t imagine what do female programmers feel or think with these kind of phrases being thrown around regularly by people who are leading or are part of the open-source movement. Programming is not a macho profession or something that men control. There maybe more men doing it but I believe that this is the profession’s loss. I am glad that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/2508746"&gt;some people correct themselves&lt;/a&gt; and I hope it happens more often. Another good read is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.fogcreek.com/girls-go-geek-again/"&gt;this blog on programming as a male profession&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;cite&gt;Fog Creek’s&lt;/cite&gt; blog by Anna Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, I was excited in the beginning to be sitting and chatting and getting to know the insights of the world of core-members and GNU but it was rather disappointing because of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Friend Firefly</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/friend-firefly" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-06-24:blog/friend-firefly</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about the rest of the world but since I first saw a firefly in rural India about 25 years ago, I have never been able to ignore them. They are those fascinating living stars that come out at twilight, flickering, glowing in neon lights. To me, they are mesmerizing because they give a feeling of how we imagine stars to be like. So, if you have been amidst a thousand of these little miracles, you’ll know. I had a moment like that a few days ago and since then, every night I cannot resist going to the field nearby, which is lit by fireflies during summer nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5039/7185396821_3dd6edf40b_z.jpg" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5039/7185396821_3dd6edf40b_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I had a couple of good long exposures, I still longed for a picture where you can see the actual insect with it’s bottom glowing. This is difficult to capture. These little suckers fly constantly, usually in the dark, and glow sporadically. So, you are not sure which direction the “dude” will fly next. Also, I never wanted to capture any firefly to capture it’s glow, without it looking like a fluorescent bulb (that’s what happens with long exposures). Also, they stop glowing if you get too close because you are seen as a predator. So far, long exposure was my friend  until the serendipitous moment yesterday right outside the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5319/7429267376_998b4294c5_z.jpg" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5319/7429267376_998b4294c5_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a moment when I was just walking towards home from parking lot and this little guy was sitting and glowing. I lay flat on the walkway just to get close enough with whatever settings my camera was on and this was the last glow it created while sitting and then flew off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I always wanted to capture a firefly and make it my friend, forever. I guess this picture gets close enough. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Eclipse Encoding Pain</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/eclipse-encoding-pain" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-05-24:blog/eclipse-encoding-pain</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you have used eclipse IDE and worked with Unicode character set then you know. I am looking at same workspace in eclipse with two files in Spanish language. One has garbage (question marks and diamonds, oh my) and the other is perfect Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have checked my settings and they are correctly pointing to UTF-8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preferences -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; workspace&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ubuntu 10.04 – Android 2.2 – LG Optimus T – Application Development Setup</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/ubuntu-1004-android-22-lg-optimus-t-application-development-setup" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-05-01:blog/ubuntu-1004-android-22-lg-optimus-t-application-development-setup</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a bunch of tries, I could figure out how to connect my LG Optimus T Android phone to my Ubuntu 10.04 development box so that I can launch and test applications directly to my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the Android &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;platform-tools/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; directory, we know that we have our famous and helpful &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;adb&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will first connect our phone through USB cable and run the command ‘lsusb’. This will give us the listing, something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;Bus 003 Device 001: ID 1d6b:0002 Linux Foundation 2.0 root hub&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the information above, we create a file: ‘/etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules’ and paste the following in the file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;usb&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;SYSFS{idVendor}==&amp;quot;618e&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;MODE=&amp;quot;0666&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;usb&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;SYSFS{idVendor}==&amp;quot;1004&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;MODE=&amp;quot;0666&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;adb &lt;span class="pre"&gt;kill-server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;adb devices&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have to reconnect the device once for the system to read and you are done.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Book: The age of entanglement</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/book-the-age-of-entanglement" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2011-11-05:blog/book-the-age-of-entanglement</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is just a collection of small excerpts from the book that I deliberately did not mark in the book itself. There are a few reasons for this and I will put some prominent ones as briefly as possible. I believe that in itself will become a review, using the excerpt-ionism as the scapegoat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the text copyrights belong to Ms. Louisa Gilder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excerpts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 57. On the streetcar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bohr, Einstein and Sommerfeld are discussing nature of light and two theories – particle nature vs wave. They miss their stop by 12 stops while discussing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“well….” says Bohr as he sits down, “I suppose during a stage in science when everything is in ferment, it cannot be expected that everybody has the same views about everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein smiles at this. “No, that is something that cannot even in the best of circumstances be expected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 81, Heisenberg in Helgoland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, out of the blue and practically crossing paths on the mail, came a paper conveying a totally different quantum mechanics. It seemed to completely contradict Heisenberg’s, yet it produced all of the same results, and – far from the thicket of matrices – did so using mathematics that any physicist could command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Schrodinger equation had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 86, What can you observe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein sat down in one of his big armchairs before the unlit fire. “Heisenberg, he said, “every theory contains unobservable quantities.” Heisenberg looked up in surprise. “the principle of employing only observable quantities simply cannot be consistently carried out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But isn’t that precisely what you’ve been doing with relativity?” asked Heisenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein smiled a little. “Perhaps I did use such philosophy earlier, perhaps I even wrote it, but it is nonsense all the same.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heisenberg looked as if he were being told by his priest that he did not actually believed in God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 113, Solvay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Like a game of chess, Einstein all the time with new examples,” Ehrenfest described to his students the subsequent Bohr-Einstein debate, which filled all the extracurricular conference time. Considering his own distaste for both unclear speaking and smelly pipe smoke, Ehrenfest found apt metaphors at hand: “Bohr from out of the philosophical smoke clouds constantly searching for the tools to crush one example after the other. Einstein like a jack-in-the-box; jumping out fresh every morning. Oh, that was priceless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, after Einstein had asked for the umpteenth time if Bohr really believed that God played dice to determine the future, a smile dawned on Bohr’s face. “Einstein,” he said, “stop telling God how to run the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 134, Things fall apart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Von Neumann’s book was a tour de force of elegant and fearsome mathematics, the sort of things most physicists never read, but its existence and conclusions were deeply consoling. The phrase “von Neumann has shown…” entered the quantum physicist’s lexicon as a debate ender.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 136, Things fall apart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurs at the Cavendish lab experiment, the Rutherford’s place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Rutherford stormed good-naturedly in and out, giving orders, encouragment, or distraction, occasionally shocking himself by hanging his wet coat on the live terminal or lighting overdry tobacco and sending it up “like a volcano with a great cloud of smoke, flames, and piles of ash,”as the experimentalist next door to Crockfort and Walton noticed with amusement. And on either April 13 or 14 – Crockfort and Walton in their notebooks wrote different dates – he observed the scintillations as the pieces of the atom hit the fluorescent screen. We’ve split the atom! This jubilant cry was soon heard at the newspapers – the atom, the unsplittable, has been split. Things fall apart; the center cannot hold.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 160, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small piece after the EPR paper from Einstein, Podolsky, Rosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While we have thus shown that the wave function does not provide a complete description of the physical reality, we have left open the question of whether or not such a description exists. We believe, however, that such a theory is possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podolsky had to leave for California at about the time of paper’s submission, and it is not clear that Einstein saw it before he was suddenly confronted, on May 4, 1935 (eleven days before the paper appeared in Physical Review), with an article on page 11 of the Saturday New York Times entitled “EINSTEIN ATTACKS QUANTUM THEORY,” complete with a hundred-word exegesis that the newspaper attributed to Podolsky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 168, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
It all came down to the relationship of Schrödinger’s equation to reality. What is the connection between the mathematical description of events, and the events themselves? In what way does the Schrödinger wavefunction, Ψ, reflect the actual state that a particle fount itself in? Reality, or the particle’s real situation, is represented in these discussions by the word state or the phrase state of affairs. The wavefunction, Ψ, must represent this real state of affairs somehow. But it is hard to even articulate what was meant by such a connection to reality, or even what was meant by reality or state.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 176, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…And even in when entering on topics apparently far removed from the problems under debate at our meetingsI have, so to speak, been arguing with Einstein all the time.”
Moved, Pais looked up at Bohr, whose voice was dropping as he circled. “I have been arguing with Einstein all the time…I have been arguing with Einstein…” He paced, slower and slower, hands behind his back, muttering, “Einstein…Einstein…” and finally stopped, gazing out the window, without seeing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assistant’s door soundlessly swung open behind him, and Einstein himself tiptoed into the room. There was “an urchin smile on his face,” and he signaled to Pais to be silent. “I was at a loss what to do,” remembered Pais, “especially because I had at that moment not the faintest idea of what Einstein was up to.” Very quietly Einstein lifted the lid of Bohr’s tobacco pot, and began to fill his pipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that moment, Bohr got his thought and spun around. “Einstein is -” and he stopped in complete shock. “There they were, face to face, as if Bohr had summoned his forth.” wrote Pais. “It is an understatement to say that for a moment Bohr was speechless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am sorry, Bohr,” said Einstein, as Bohr burst out laughing. “But you know my doctor forbade me to buy tobacco.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 177, The Quantum-Mechanical Description of Reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neils Bohr died next year. On his blackboard were left two drawings, a record of what he had been thinking about the night before he died. The first looked like a spiral staircase – A Riemann surface – which was Bohr’s favorite metaphor for the ambiguity of language, the way you can arrive back at the same word in your thought and it can have a whole new layer of meaning than when you first thought it. But how, he used to ask, can you communicate this to another person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second drawing, almost vibrating on its chalky spring, was Einstein’s light-filled box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page 185, The Search And The Idictment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
David Bohm is called before committee…
“He used to joke about it,” remembered his student Ken Ford, “real gallows humor. There was a faculty lecture on unresolvable paradoxes – If the barder is the man who shaves all men, who do not shave themselves, who shaves the barder? – “and Dave said that ‘Congress should appoint a committee to investigate all committees that do not investigate themselves.’”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Women In tech and harassment they face</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/women-in-tech-and-harassment-they-face" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2011-10-28:blog/women-in-tech-and-harassment-they-face</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://geekfeminism.org/2011/10/13/on-being-harassed-a-little-gf-history-and-some-current-events/"&gt;Read this article of a woman in tech where she explains the harassment she faces in this industry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have these men forgotten that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/brainiac/2011/07/the_computer_gi.html"&gt;programming was primarily considered a women’s profession at one point&lt;/a&gt;? Have they forgotten that Ada Lovelace is usually cited as the first programmer? And above all, have they forgotten their decency? I think there wasn’t any decency in these pigs to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if their mothers wanted to be in tech?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what women in tech need are more women and more support from the community. Let me rephrase that, what everyone in tech needs today is more women. Also, to boot off anyone who is found guilty of behaving like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Android’s ACTION_CALL is restricted, duh!</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/androids-action_call-is-restricted-duh" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2011-02-16:blog/androids-action_call-is-restricted-duh</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have an Android app called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/callHelp"&gt;CallHelp (Call Help)&lt;/a&gt;. It is a simple application where you have a one large button which supposedly calls  911 (emergency number). Intention of the app is to have a quick way to call 911 by pressing the button and keeping it pressed till the time they do not want to call. Releasing the button will/should call 911.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem with current implementation is that it does not automatically call 911. It just pulls up the dial screen with 911 number pre-filled. I was trying to figure out a way to make calls but I guess I cannot do it. This is because the Android Intent called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Intent.html#ACTION_CALL"&gt;ACTION_CALL&lt;/a&gt; is restricted to non-emergency number and I have to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Intent.html#ACTION_DIAL"&gt;ACTION_DIAL&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the fun part is that I cannot create my app the way I want to because it just won’t dial 911. After releasing the huge button in my app, you have to press “Call” on the next screen. This just fails my app’s core purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this app has a good usage. For example, someone moving through a dark alley might want to keep such a ‘setup’ ready in case something happens. You know, at least there will be a call to 911 (say, even if the phone drops etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amanjeev.com/a-very-simple-android-application-for-safety.html"&gt;Older post about this app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Book Review: CSS Mastery</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/book-review-css-mastery" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2010-09-24:blog/book-review-css-mastery</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amzn.com/1430223979"&gt;CSS Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, it seems, is for anyone who works with CSS. It is a very helpful book for people who are new to CSS and want a well-written book that is easy to understand. I found the book extremely helpful as a thorough read and as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://andybudd.com/"&gt;Andy Budd&lt;/a&gt;, is a famous UX and Usability specialist. He has done a nice job with this book. To be honest, I actually have some permanent bookmarks that I go to when I need advice. Be it the foundations or the bugs chapter, they are worth keeping bookmarked. He starts with structuring your code, teaching better semantics and strategies. He also covers various techniques which are important as a CSS developer like FIR. I also like that he covered formatting links, lists and forms. At the end of the book, there are two great case-studies which are very helpful for someone who wants to begin front-end web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just have one gripe which is not a big anyway. I hope that he had a separate chapter or section for CSS3 standard rather than it being within each chapter. A separate section would have been awesome for people who are trying to get on the CSS3 bandwagon. In short, this is a great book for a day-to-day CSS developer to keep by his/her side.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SSH RSYNC Dreamhost Backup User</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/ssh-rsync-dreamhost-backup-user" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2010-08-08:blog/ssh-rsync-dreamhost-backup-user</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps someone. I was trying to have rsync setup with Dreamhost’s 50GB free backup plan to backup my machine without having to type the password again and having to interfere with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I did the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created the Backup User using the CPanel and once created, logged in using SFTP into the backup user account (it gives you a different account/username).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then created a directory named .ssh in the root of this new account (remember I am logged in sing SFTP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put my &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;id_rsa.pub&lt;/tt&gt; in this directory and renamed it to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;authorized_key&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, I thought things were fine and fired the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;rsync &lt;span class="pre"&gt;-e&lt;/span&gt; ssh &lt;span class="pre"&gt;-av&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;&amp;#64;.dreamhost.com:~/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please make sure that you do not generate SSH key with a passphrase and also have right permissions.  It needs 700 for the private key.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Very Simple Android Application for Safety</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/a-very-simple-android-application-for-safety" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2009-12-16:blog/a-very-simple-android-application-for-safety</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally got to play with Android and I tried to make it useful enough. This application is not a big break-through or something 2.0-ish. Its a very simple call app but I am under this assumption that this will prove to be useful (at least it will be for me if I had an Android phone). Yes, I do not have Android phone and I do not even have an iPhone. I just happen to suck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is about Calling for help when you are walking through a dark or a possibly unsafe place. Hoping that you are getting phone signal, I have always wondered that instead of fidgeting with your phone to dial 911 and keeping your thumb on the “green call” button, why not have an application where there is a big fat button that when released calls 911. Thats what I have tried to do here in this application. A 200px button when pressed and held, does not do anything, but when released, dials 911. So, you can save yourself from a surprise event like someone attacking you from behind and leave the calling for the app to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amanjeev.com/pg/callHelp30.apk"&gt;Here is the .apk file of the application&lt;/a&gt;. I call it callHelp application. I think its a good idea to improve this application to include a setting where you can change the emergency number (I’d suggest keep 911). Right now this feature is not there because I am not even sure if this application works on a handset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in looking at the source code, you can do that here at Github. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/amanjeev/CallHelp"&gt;Source code at Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if someone out there tries it, please let me know how goes it! thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>