<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/photography.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2013-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Photography and Charity</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/photography-and-charity" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-09-11:blog/photography-and-charity</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this excellent photographer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://earthincolors.wordpress.com"&gt;Moyan Brenn&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aigle_dore/"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/Moyan_brenn"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;], who happens to have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://earthincolors.wordpress.com/my-international-charity-campaign/"&gt;charity campaign&lt;/a&gt;. On his charity web page where he urges everyone to join. He says -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Every month i am personally sending 20 dollars to a little boy in Africa……with my photo gallery i’m trying to involve people in donating money to the third world….it’s my main objective and why i want my pictures to be spread over the world. I have something beautiful to communicate which lies behind the strong colors of my pictures, and want it to be useful for those suffering in the third world&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He goes on to explain further on how you can join the charity campaign -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, optionally, if you can afford it and you really appreciate my works, I kindly invite you to make a donation, or to help me to diffuse my pictures by linking my blog in your website just if you decide to use my pictures, or, still, by inviting other people to use them for free and to donate as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do it, by sending me a receipt of the donation by email, your name will be inserted in the acknowledgement list below, and in the acknowledgement list reported in my flickr profile, where i will also include a link to your website or blog if you need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed it and have not visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aigle_dore/"&gt;his flickr&lt;/a&gt;, you should do that now because he really is a great photographer and I am sure a lot of us can make use of his photographs and skills. I also really liked the idea and model of his charity. He is passionate about photography and charity and he is achieving both here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally have mentioned my charity effort on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/amanjeev"&gt;my 500px page&lt;/a&gt; as -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Any purchase of my pictures or any donation for my work will go to the humanitarian causes. I am not affiliated to these organizations and you are free to donate to these yourself.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.prajwalaindia.com/home.html"&gt;Prajwala&lt;/a&gt; [for the victims of sex trafficking]&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, so far I have &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16964325"&gt;sold only one photograph&lt;/a&gt; (amounts to $2 at this point). Then this morning I realized that maybe people are skeptic of such purchases. Maybe, they think that I am raking in cash and not donating (although looking at my amateur skills, it is evident I ain't selling a lot). I'd be skeptic about this too. Funny that when we donate to a charity, the transparency we demand from the charity is so high. I wish we did this with for-profit companies also. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/500px_Help/status/377788159100452864"&gt;I contacted 500px over twitter&lt;/a&gt; regarding this. The idea is simple - prove the authenticity of a photographer's charity status to the potential buyers. Here are some key points that I thought of -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500px acts as a mediator between charities/non-profits and photographer's purchases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One can easily connect to and build a list of various non-profits around the globe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographers can display how much percentage of their profits from 500px do they want to donate to the charities but this will be displayed on their profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since, 500px is the mediator, they can control these donations and award a so called - Charity Badge - to the photographer to be displayed on the profile. This alone will give confidence of the users/buyers to purchase something from someone who donates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographers can also list non-profits they donate to on their respective profile to facilitate this further. The more details in the profile, more will be user confidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unaware of the legalities involved but I don't see how it will be a big deal, except that 500px will have to do a lot of work and being a startup they might have to run the numbers on how beneficial this will be for them. So, maybe we (the Phogrammers or Protographers) can use 500px's API to create a service that lets people achieve this without 500px having to do all the work? I am not sure yet, but I think this is a start in some kind of charity campaign that can get passionate photographers make an effort to sell more and buyers of their work to make more humanitarian choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Photo: Unused bench gathers a lot of moss</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-10-21:blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="" src="http://pcdn.500px.net/16341429/ea700652f238ad65807bdfe9c06ff1f5b0a92a15/4.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341429"&gt;Unused bench gathers a lot of moss&lt;/a&gt; is now in the Popular pictures’ set on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/"&gt;500px (the photography website)&lt;/a&gt;. I also have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341455"&gt;B&amp;amp;W version of this picture&lt;/a&gt; which has amazing texture of this bench but I guess more folks in the world have better/more &lt;cite&gt;cone cells&lt;/cite&gt; in their eyes than I do. My response to the B&amp;amp;W picture was more positive than this one, even though I love this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken in the American University, Washington D.C. Photography can be very unpredictable when it comes to subjects. One can have as many themes and one can keep on shooting the entire day but the best piece of the day may certainly be something you just randomly clicked. For my future self, I need to remember two things -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click more and more. I am not paying for the film so why not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step outside of the subject boundary and not be confined. This will take a lot of effort despite the fact that I know it very well that I have to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck because this is a fortuitous profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>10000</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/10000" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-09-21:blog/10000</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I believe that every computer programmer should know about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html"&gt;Norvig’s Teach Yourself Programming in Ten Years&lt;/a&gt;. If you have not read it, give it a go. It is an excellent piece of advice. So, if you have not heard about the 10,000 hour rule then you should also read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316017930/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=profeblogs0df-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0316017930"&gt;Outliers: The Story of Success&lt;/a&gt; by Malcolm Gladwell. The author is trying to say that to be a ‘superlative’ in your trade, you need to invest 10,000 hours in it. To be clear, 10,000 hours is the rule not to be just good or very good; it is to be somebody who is unrivaled in that trade. This, according to Mr. Gladwell, applies everywhere. So, this should apply to Photography as well. I recently started photography as a hobby and very recently read this quote -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;Your first 10,000 photographs are your worst.&amp;quot; -Henri Cartier-Bresson&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have some doubts. Here are some&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are those 10,000 hours related to 10,000 photographs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, what kind of 10,000 photographs are those?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do multiple shots of one object/subject count as one photograph or multiple?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How about shots that you take while testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Friend Firefly</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/friend-firefly" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-06-24:blog/friend-firefly</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about the rest of the world but since I first saw a firefly in rural India about 25 years ago, I have never been able to ignore them. They are those fascinating living stars that come out at twilight, flickering, glowing in neon lights. To me, they are mesmerizing because they give a feeling of how we imagine stars to be like. So, if you have been amidst a thousand of these little miracles, you’ll know. I had a moment like that a few days ago and since then, every night I cannot resist going to the field nearby, which is lit by fireflies during summer nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5039/7185396821_3dd6edf40b_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I had a couple of good long exposures, I still longed for a picture where you can see the actual insect with it’s bottom glowing. This is difficult to capture. These little suckers fly constantly, usually in the dark, and glow sporadically. So, you are not sure which direction the “dude” will fly next. Also, I never wanted to capture any firefly to capture it’s glow, without it looking like a fluorescent bulb (that’s what happens with long exposures). Also, they stop glowing if you get too close because you are seen as a predator. So far, long exposure was my friend  until the serendipitous moment yesterday right outside the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5319/7429267376_998b4294c5_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a moment when I was just walking towards home from parking lot and this little guy was sitting and glowing. I lay flat on the walkway just to get close enough with whatever settings my camera was on and this was the last glow it created while sitting and then flew off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I always wanted to capture a firefly and make it my friend, forever. I guess this picture gets close enough. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>