<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/Photography.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Photo: Unused bench gathers a lot of moss</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-10-21:blog/photo-unused-bench-gathers-a-lot-of-moss</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="http://pcdn.500px.net/16341429/ea700652f238ad65807bdfe9c06ff1f5b0a92a15/4.jpg" src="http://pcdn.500px.net/16341429/ea700652f238ad65807bdfe9c06ff1f5b0a92a15/4.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341429"&gt;Unused bench gathers a lot of moss&lt;/a&gt; is now in the Popular pictures’ set on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/"&gt;500px (the photography website)&lt;/a&gt;. I also have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://500px.com/photo/16341455"&gt;B&amp;amp;W version of this picture&lt;/a&gt; which has amazing texture of this bench but I guess more folks in the world have better/more &lt;cite&gt;cone cells&lt;/cite&gt; in their eyes than I do. My response to the B&amp;amp;W picture was more positive than this one, even though I love this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken in the American University, Washington D.C. Photography can be very unpredictable when it comes to subjects. One can have as many themes and one can keep on shooting the entire day but the best piece of the day may certainly be something you just randomly clicked. For my future self, I need to remember two things -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click more and more. I am not paying for the film so why not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step outside of the subject boundary and not be confined. This will take a lot of effort despite the fact that I know it very well that I have to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck because this is a fortuitous profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>10000</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/10000" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-09-21:blog/10000</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I believe that every computer programmer should know about the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html"&gt;Norvig’s Teach Yourself Programming in Ten Years&lt;/a&gt;. If you have not read it, give it a go. It is an excellent piece of advice. So, if you have not heard about the 10,000 hour rule then you should also read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316017930/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=profeblogs0df-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0316017930"&gt;Outliers: The Story of Success&lt;/a&gt; by Malcolm Gladwell. The author is trying to say that to be a ‘superlative’ in your trade, you need to invest 10,000 hours in it. To be clear, 10,000 hours is the rule not to be just good or very good; it is to be somebody who is unrivaled in that trade. This, according to Mr. Gladwell, applies everywhere. So, this should apply to Photography as well. I recently started photography as a hobby and very recently read this quote -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;quot;Your first 10,000 photographs are your worst.&amp;quot; -Henri Cartier-Bresson&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have some doubts. Here are some&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are those 10,000 hours related to 10,000 photographs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, what kind of 10,000 photographs are those?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do multiple shots of one object/subject count as one photograph or multiple?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How about shots that you take while testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Friend Firefly</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/friend-firefly" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-06-24:blog/friend-firefly</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about the rest of the world but since I first saw a firefly in rural India about 25 years ago, I have never been able to ignore them. They are those fascinating living stars that come out at twilight, flickering, glowing in neon lights. To me, they are mesmerizing because they give a feeling of how we imagine stars to be like. So, if you have been amidst a thousand of these little miracles, you’ll know. I had a moment like that a few days ago and since then, every night I cannot resist going to the field nearby, which is lit by fireflies during summer nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5039/7185396821_3dd6edf40b_z.jpg" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5039/7185396821_3dd6edf40b_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I had a couple of good long exposures, I still longed for a picture where you can see the actual insect with it’s bottom glowing. This is difficult to capture. These little suckers fly constantly, usually in the dark, and glow sporadically. So, you are not sure which direction the “dude” will fly next. Also, I never wanted to capture any firefly to capture it’s glow, without it looking like a fluorescent bulb (that’s what happens with long exposures). Also, they stop glowing if you get too close because you are seen as a predator. So far, long exposure was my friend  until the serendipitous moment yesterday right outside the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5319/7429267376_998b4294c5_z.jpg" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5319/7429267376_998b4294c5_z.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a moment when I was just walking towards home from parking lot and this little guy was sitting and glowing. I lay flat on the walkway just to get close enough with whatever settings my camera was on and this was the last glow it created while sitting and then flew off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I always wanted to capture a firefly and make it my friend, forever. I guess this picture gets close enough. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>