<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amanjeev Sethi</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amanjeev.com/feeds/random.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amanjeev.com/</id><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Customer Management Effort</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/customer-management-effort" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2013-01-14:blog/customer-management-effort</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is just a collection two nice personal customer management stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="charity-water"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charity Water&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I donated some money to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.charitywater.org"&gt;Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;. I have donated money to some of the well-known organizations, from large sized to some smaller than Charity Water. I have never received a hand-written, address-to-me letter/card from any organization before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Letter from charity water, scanned copy" class="align-center" src="/img/charity_water_card.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 406px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amanjeev.com/img/charity_water_card.jpg"&gt;You can see a scanned copy of the card from Charity Water&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I have been wondering if this is the right thing to do. It seems obvious that this is a very good strategy to thank the existing customers and keep them happy. I know that this is an effort to make things more personal for me and it feels great. I donated to their cause so I already was aligned with what they are doing and this personally written letter makes it easy to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is the first charity to explicitly mention it to me that a 100% of my donations will go to the cause. This maybe a minor thing but I felt that this was a nice little statement to get my trust. Thank you Charity Water for sending a card to me that looks like you put an effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bustedtees"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BustedTees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company knows how to please their customers. I ordered a bunch of T-shirts and a few crazy things from them a while ago and asked for a 2-day shipping. For some reason, on the 4th day I suspected that my package was stolen or misplaced. I called their customer service with only the order number in my hand. It took about 3 minutes for the entire conversation for the customer representative to arrive at a conclusion - &lt;em&gt;Ship me another order with the same items immediately&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;And they did!&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later I also recieved the original package. Luckily, BustedTees had already sent me a UPS box to return the extra items. I had to do, nothing expect for making that call to their customer service department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I have an Indian passport but I need Nationality Verification form. What!?</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-07-15:blog/i-have-an-indian-passport-but-i-need-nationality-verification-form-what</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If you are looking for the Nationality Verification form of India then you may want to go to the website of Consulate General. I do not take any responsibility of anything. This blog post is a rant.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to get my passport renewed. As expected the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indiacgny.org/"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.indianembassy.org/"&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://indiacgny.org/php/showContent.php?linkid=225"&gt;portals&lt;/a&gt; of Indian government are useless. Fortunately, they have outsourced the process to another company – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/"&gt;VFS Global&lt;/a&gt;. So, I stumbled upon the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/india/usa/addition_of_spouse_docreq.html"&gt;Documents Required page&lt;/a&gt;. That’s where the funny part is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Print out of Online Application form (Total of 4 pages). (When you click this link, if your browser says ‘There is a problem with the website security certificate’, &lt;em&gt;then please click the option 'Continue to this website (not recommended)'. This is because the link is an external site but is reliable as it is maintained by Government of India)&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the government cannot reliably provide the information, I am not sure if I can call other resources of it being reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in that list there is a required form -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Nationality Verification Form&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am giving my passport (issued by the Government of India) to them (the Government) and they want to see another form that proves my nationality. Is there any other way you can get a passport of India? Maybe someone can enlighten me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus – &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jammukashmir.nic.in/"&gt;The website of the beautiful state of Jammu and Kashmir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Macho Developers and the Clique</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/macho-developers-and-the-clique" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2012-07-13:blog/macho-developers-and-the-clique</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently met someone during my travel to work, in the train. I will not name this certain someone but just know that he is apparently a talented FOSS contributor and is related to GNU.org. I will call him Mr. X. In general, X was friendly. He caught me writing some code in the train and assumed I was writing JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: Are you writing JavaScript?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: Anything that colorful could only be JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ (ummmm... it's the editor]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Are you a programmer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X: I don’t write JavaScript. I am a C hacker. Kernel hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[At this point I did not realize there was a bit mocking tone to his &amp;quot;I don't write JavaScript&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I didn’t have to ask a lot and a lot of talking was done by Mr. X. Mostly nice talk but a couple of things however, got stuck with me since that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The clique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, “He does not write anything that cannot be written with C“. There was a sense of superiority in his style of conversation. “Moi poor web developer”, I thought. I like open-source software and use it everyday. I really wish that this attitude changes amongst the developer community. I really respect your knowledge but it hurts if you lack humility and respect for others, especially the ones who aspire to contribute and support the open-source software and community. This attitude makes it harder for everyone. I am glad that there are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kennethreitz.com/be-cordial-or-be-on-your-way.html"&gt;posts like this&lt;/a&gt; which support this view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Us Macho Programmers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/macho"&gt;macho&lt;/a&gt; : aggressively virile; a man who is aggressively proud of his masculinity.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard the phrase Us macho programmers at least thrice in the conversation. I do not appreciate this. What this conveys to me is that the real programmers are the knights, which in turn, are only masculine. This equates macho with programmers. I have nothing much to say on this issue except that it discouraged me from pursuing being a part of this group he was talking about which I mentioned about in the clique. If I, a male programmer, got discouraged then I can’t imagine what do female programmers feel or think with these kind of phrases being thrown around regularly by people who are leading or are part of the open-source movement. Programming is not a macho profession or something that men control. There maybe more men doing it but I believe that this is the profession’s loss. I am glad that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/2508746"&gt;some people correct themselves&lt;/a&gt; and I hope it happens more often. Another good read is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.fogcreek.com/girls-go-geek-again/"&gt;this blog on programming as a male profession&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;cite&gt;Fog Creek’s&lt;/cite&gt; blog by Anna Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, I was excited in the beginning to be sitting and chatting and getting to know the insights of the world of core-members and GNU but it was rather disappointing because of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Women In tech and harassment they face</title><link href="http://amanjeev.com/blog/women-in-tech-and-harassment-they-face" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amanjeev Sethi</name></author><id>tag:amanjeev.com,2011-10-28:blog/women-in-tech-and-harassment-they-face</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://geekfeminism.org/2011/10/13/on-being-harassed-a-little-gf-history-and-some-current-events/"&gt;Read this article of a woman in tech where she explains the harassment she faces in this industry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have these men forgotten that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/brainiac/2011/07/the_computer_gi.html"&gt;programming was primarily considered a women’s profession at one point&lt;/a&gt;? Have they forgotten that Ada Lovelace is usually cited as the first programmer? And above all, have they forgotten their decency? I think there wasn’t any decency in these pigs to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if their mothers wanted to be in tech?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what women in tech need are more women and more support from the community. Let me rephrase that, what everyone in tech needs today is more women. Also, to boot off anyone who is found guilty of behaving like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>